Rory Malone

70 Waterloo Avenue, Leiston, Suffolk, IP16 4HE rory.malone@hotmail.com mob: +44 7450889988

PROFILE

An accomplished full stack developer with attention to detail and a perfectionist when building modern web applications. I have built a successful career using the latest technologies and have proven management skills leading a product download hub. Facing challenge using myriad experience and critical thinking I am always keen to lead and assist colleagues in the industry.

EDUCATION

Computer Science BSc September 2014 – 2017

First class honors

University of East London London, UK

ENTERPRISE TECHNOLOGIES

Typescript, Node, Microsoft Azure, React, Redux, HTML5, Sass, Webpack, GraphQL, Express, SQL, REST, OAuth 2.0

OTHER SKILLS

UX, SDL, DevOps, crunch, GIT workflow, Unix

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Full Stack Developer

ARM holdings ltd. Cambridge, UK

August 2019 – Present

Leading the development of a responsive web-app for high profile customers to download CPU intellectual property for one of the worlds best known semiconductor companies.

My responsibilities include:

- Provide technical leadership for an agile team of developers and ensure the quality of the product is delivered with concise, well structured code.
- Translate complex business requirements from the product owner into arcane technical specifications and delegate to team members.
- Pioneering and rapid prototyping of high performance full stack solutions to phase out older technologies and practices.
- Responsible for deploying entire software stacks globally, configuring continuous zero-downtime delivery pipelines and alerting in Azure.
- Using the power of events and metrics to track user stories and model flows across our micro-services architecture to address latency and failures.
- Aggregate user events into metrics to drive the conception of new features.
- Presenting the above to upper business management and developers to prove the effectiveness of solutions.
- Key member of hiring team responsible for screening and interviewing new developers.
- Provide technical assistance for fellow developers of all abilities.

British Telecom PLC Ipswich, UK

September 2017 - August 2019

- In a focused team at the heart of the company I have enjoyed developing software that links the cores business units together
- Building highly deployable, lightweight applications in the form of micro-services.
- Pioneering a new client server architecture to improve the process of authentication and authorization of our web applications.
- Front end strategy team player. I was responsible for pitching powerful presentations
 to illustrate ambitions for modernizing the team methodology and practices for the
 development and delivery of our products.

Key projects and deliverables:

- 999 Management Portal: A web interface for managing emergency service numbers, agents and various other facets, I was the front end developer responsible for delivering this important service for the upcoming upgrade of the 999 infrastructure.
- **Big Data Dashboard**: Extensively improving real time delivery of precise business data to BT executives. I designed and implemented an interface to display key information for monitoring BT product sales performance. Delivering an entire stack written in node, building dynamic elasticsearch queries to save time and resources for high level executives.
- Service Gateway: Building scalable REST API that all of our products go through, I was a key developer in maintaining and implementing features for our API layer, a Node.js application that requires constant updates and testing to remain a reliable and secure server that all of our products rely on.
- Cisco services portal: Leading a team, I was managing the modernization of a service for BT customers to manage their business devices and features. Meeting the latest technology standards to deliver a versatile product to appeal to a wider international customer base.